Hello everyone, in this video, we will learn about the new feature of the 2024 version, the sewing wrinkle.
Sewing wrinkle is used to show the fine wrinkle caused by the difference in tension between the fabric and the sewing line.
You can refer to this picture, the position of the sewing line or the line will have some effect of sewing wrinkle.
Sewing wrinkle is most commonly used to make cowboy clothes.
If you look at these cowboy clothes on Kinect, you will see that there are all kinds of sewing wrinkle effects in the sewing line position.
Due to the different water washing effects on the clothes, the sewing wrinkle is either strong or weak.
Sewing wrinkle is not limited to cowboy clothing, but it can also be used for this kind of leisure clothing.
Although it can get a more real wrinkle effect by making the mesh grid smaller,
but using this kind of mesh grid or fabric pattern of sewing wrinkle can create a similar effect without changing the premise of the version.
Now let's take a look at the sewing wrinkle function.
The sewing wrinkle tool is located in the 2D tool bar.
You can also find it in the material download menu of the main menu.
We have a separate window to manage the type of sewing wrinkle.
Click on the triangle next to the window title to switch to the parkering type window.
You can display the menu in the 2D or 3D window bar.
You can also change whether the sewing wrinkle that has been created is displayed.
In a strange situation, when you choose the sewing wrinkle tool, the thread of the sewing wrinkle will be displayed in purple.
Next, let's take a look at the sewing wrinkle tool.
In the 2D tool bar, next to the line tool is the sewing wrinkle tool.
There are four related tools.
Editing sewing wrinkle, thread sewing wrinkle, free sewing wrinkle, and sewing wrinkle sewing wrinkle tool.
Just like the line tool group.
Now let's try these tools.
You can use the file in the top comment to test.
First is the thread sewing wrinkle tool.
It is used to create sewing wrinkle on a thread.
If you create sewing wrinkle on a board in a symmetrical relationship, it will automatically create on a symmetrical board.
Free sewing wrinkle tool is used to create free sewing wrinkle along the thread.
You can freely select the starting point and the end point.
Click on the starting point and then click on the end point to create the sewing wrinkle.
Thread sewing wrinkle is used to create sewing wrinkle on both sides of the thread at the same time.
It can only be applied by selecting the thread sewing wrinkle.
By editing the sewing wrinkle tool, you can select the sewing wrinkle that has been created.
Move a whole sewing wrinkle or move the end point of the sewing wrinkle.
Please note that the sewing wrinkle cannot overlap the thread sewing wrinkle.
Next, let's take a look at the properties of sewing wrinkle.
First, let's create the sewing wrinkle on the pocket version.
When you select the created sewing wrinkle, you will see the single object property of the sewing wrinkle in the property editor.
You can set its name, switch the type of sewing wrinkle, select whether to extend or set the diameter.
Extend is an option.
Select whether to extend the two ends of the sewing wrinkle you have selected to the outside of the pattern.
If you turn off any extension, you will see that the sewing wrinkle will only be created within the right angle of the point at the end.
Thread sewing wrinkle is used to set the distance between the sewing wrinkle and its thread.
Thread sewing wrinkle is used to set the distance between the sewing wrinkle texture and the pattern.
It is very useful when the sewing wrinkle is stacked in the same place with the line.
For the sewing wrinkle of the sewing line, there is an option to set the position of the sewing wrinkle.
In the default setting, the sewing wrinkle of the sewing line is automatically created on both sides of the sewing line, but you can also set any side that is only created in it.
If you create a sewing wrinkle on the internal line, you can turn the menu in the object physics property.
You can turn the sewing wrinkle to the other side of the line.
Next, let's take a look at the window type of sewing wrinkle.
Click on the window VL name to find the part green in the menu below to change the window.
The sewing wrinkle window is similar to other object-type windows.
At the top, there are buttons to add, copy, apply, and delete unused buttons.
Select the tool to edit the sewing wrinkle.
The right-click on the sewing wrinkle line will pop up a menu.
You can select all sewing wrinkle types that have the same properties or delete sewing wrinkle.
Select all sewing wrinkle types that have the same properties or delete sewing wrinkle.
Use the new sewing wrinkle.
Add a new, default sewing wrinkle type and apply it to the selected sewing wrinkle object.
When you choose a sewing wrinkle type, its properties will appear in the property editor below.
First, here, the sewing wrinkle type can be opened or saved through the PTP document format.
At the bottom of the property, you can change the preset style of the sewing wrinkle.
There are cotton, denim, leather, nylon, and dylen.
In the default situation, the sewing wrinkle is just a hairstyle sticker.
But you can add a texture sticker for it.
The texture with transparency will bring more different effects to your sewing wrinkle.
At the bottom of the texture option, you can click to choose whether the color is medium or light.
You can control the texture effect by the intensity of the bottom of the texture.
You can also modify the color and transparency of the texture.
In the specifications, you can adjust the thickness of the sewing wrinkle by the density.
In order to create a thinner or thicker wrinkle effect.
The width is used to adjust the width of the sewing wrinkle.
The sewing wrinkle is usually used together with the line.
They may be added in the same place.
As in the video, the outline of the panel has been added to the line.
We need to create a sewing wrinkle.
First, select the line of the sewing wrinkle tool.
Click on the outline of the panel.
Then select the type of sewing wrinkle to be used in the sewing wrinkle window.
Increase the strength of the texture sticker in the property editor.
You can see that the effect is very obvious now.
I want the sewing wrinkle to look like it is created along the line.
So I use the editor sewing wrinkle tool to select the sewing wrinkle object.
Then modify its diameter.
At this time, we will reduce the diameter again.
Let the sewing wrinkle overlap slightly with the line.
Then select the type of sewing wrinkle.
Because the material is cowhide, we do not need to modify the preset type.
Continue to use cotton cloth.
In order to make the sewing wrinkle look more like a water wash.
Add a pattern.
Click on the pattern option on the right side of the browser.
Select a suitable pattern.
You can open Materials, Hardware and Trims, Pockering.
Select Cotton and click Open.
To make it look more white and closer to the water wash effect.
Reduce density and number.
Can make the sewing wrinkle thinner.
You can also adjust the width of the sewing wrinkle according to your needs.
In this example, we have made several types of sewing wrinkle in advance.
Now we add sewing wrinkle to the collar and the sleeve.
Select Double Stitch this sewing wrinkle.
Then use the free sewing wrinkle tool and the modern sewing wrinkle tool to create a sewing wrinkle.
Use the editor sewing wrinkle tool to press the Shift key.
At the same time, select the sewing wrinkle in the collar and the sleeve position.
Go to the property editor.
Adjust the number of columns.
Let the sewing wrinkle start from the first obvious position.
That's all about the sewing wrinkle functions.
Thank you for watching.
See you in the next video.